YOU AND EVERYTHING ELSE
Please join Cheerleading Club!
One, two, let's go! One, two…
You just might be the lucky one!
We're Game Club!
We're Photography Club!
MAGIC HOUR PHOTOGRAPHY CLUB
First, you can sign up for our registry…
If I learn photography here,
would I be able to develop this roll?
Absolutely!
You're a freshman. Class of 2001, right?
Yes.
Isn't that Sang-hak?
You're right. It is.
Hey, Sang-hak!
You sure took your damn time.
- Hey, man.
- Hey.
- How's the turnout?
- This freshman brought a Tri-X roll.
She couldn't develop the film.
Why don't you take a look?
Sure.
Can I have a look at the Tri-X roll?
I hear you brought film
and asked if we could develop it.
It's this.
Did you study photography?
No.
Then where did you get this from?
I've just
had it for a long time.
Sorry for bombarding you with questions
before an introduction.
I'm Kim Sang-hak.
Business management. Class of 2000.
Never mind.
I'm Kim Sang-hak.
Business management. Class of 2000.
What significance does language have
in the way we think?
It allows us to distinguish concepts,
conceptualize habitual actions,
and generate new ideas.
If we simplify the history of mankind…
Room 207.
"Understanding Language…"
Room 207…
Hurry up!
Hey, wait up!
Is everything all right?
Did you see a film roll here?
A black-and-white one.
Did you lose that Tri-X roll
you had earlier?
Yes.
There's no other place it could be.
Sure seems like it's super important.
You ran off so quickly
you didn't hear me call you.
Thank you.
Take a seat if you're grateful.
Please.
Come on.
The least you can do
is finish what you started writing.
I had to go to the humanities office
and your lecture hall because of this.
I'm sorry.
You'll understand better next year,
but freshmen are rare in our club.
Everyone kept harping on at me
about how I scared you off.
- You didn't.
- Right?
Did you guys hear that?
- Yeah, congrats.
- Why else would she run away?
REGISTRATION FORM
RYU EUN-JUNG
Once you're done,
I'll drop the formalities.
I haven't
finished filling out the form just yet.
I apologize.
Please go ahead and fill it out.
DATE OF BIRTH: 1982…
ADDRESS: GYEONGGI-DO, ILYEONG
TO LEARN HOW TO DEVELOP
BLACK-AND-WHITE FILM…
It's Magic Hour. Welcome.
We're Magic Hour, the photography club.
A long time ago,
someone once told me this.
This was shot with a shutter speed of 60,
which means this photo captured
1/60 of a second.
They said that although
time may appear frozen in a photograph,
1/60th of a second lives on
in the photo forever.
And so to take a photograph
is to collect time.
Hey, it's me.
What?
Sang-yeon. I'm outside,
so I can't hear you well.
Say that again. What happened to Sang-hak?
He's dead.
Sang-hak's dead.
CHUNGMURO
Could you lend this to me for one week?
I promise to return it after that.
That day, Sang-hak left home
early in the morning.
Three days later,
they found him in the mountains.
Eun-jung.
The first person to answer the call
from the police…
was Sang-yeon.
What's on your mind?
- Hello.
- Hey.
Is that a camera?
- Yes. I just bought it today.
- Today?
It's secondhand. I got it today.
Can I have a look? What model is it?
- FM2.
- I see.
Shall we take a look?
Sit here.
How much did you pay for it?
It was originally 370,000 won,
but since I had to go pick it up,
the seller gave it to me for 350,000.
350,000 won?
And how far did you have to go
to pick it up?
Uijeongbu.
Uijeongbu? Yikes.
Are you free right now?
Yes.
It seems to be in decent shape.
And the lens is clean.
But this camera is fully manual.
Do you know how to use it?
I learned how a long time ago.
I learned everything
except how to change the film.
Except changing the film?
But you can adjust exposure
and shutter speed?
Yes.
Who was it?
Who taught you how to use a camera
but skipped the part about changing rolls?
Is it difficult?
Do you have a roll?
It's a Tri-X roll.
So Tri-X carries around a Tri-X roll.
The seller gave it to me as a freebie.
To put the film in,
you just need to open the back cover.
Look here.
You turn this lever counterclockwise,
then lift this rewind knob.
That's it.
You got that?
You're good.
You then insert the film here
and align these holes in the film…
with these things here.
Now turn the film advance lever
to wind the film.
Right.
Lastly, make sure the film is
tightly loaded before you close the cover.
From that moment on…
I couldn't help myself.
Whenever I would see him…
I couldn't help but freeze.
So,
is it like a dragonfly net?
To take a photograph
is to collect time, right?
To take a photograph is to collect time.
Collect lots of good moments.
See you.
Yes, well, the paper's stuck.
The machine's not returning
my copier card.
Hey!
- Hello.
- Hi.
That machine is broken, actually.
Is it really?
Yes.
Do you need three copies
of each of these pages?
Yes.
Pretty impressive, huh? This is my turf.
I mean,
I'm a work-study student this semester.
Coming through.
- I can do it.
- I'm just so helpful.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Join the research team if you're grateful.
The nicer he was to me,
the more timid I became.
Please catch it!
Thank you.
- I'm so sorry!
- It's okay!
I couldn't have made
a bigger fool of myself if I'd tried.
How embarrassing!
Let me be direct with you.
You're right to be embarrassed,
but the people who saw won't care.
- They probably thought it was funny.
- Yeah. I think it's cute.
I know. The people watching
must have found it hilarious.
That's not the problem.
- Then what is?
- I just feel so awkward.
I keep stumbling over my words.
And when he said he'd take me out
to eat that day, I just ran away.
So do you not like him?
No.
Then what's the issue?
He offers to buy you food
and copies your papers for free.
And he asked you to join his team.
Exactly! Why am I like this
when he's being nice?
So are you going to miss
the welcome party?
Of course I want to go.
- I want to go, but…
- Why are you so nervous?
Just go. Go get wasted and ask him,
"What's your deal?
Why do you make me feel this way?"
Bottoms up!
Ryu Eun-jung. Humanities.
Straight out of high school.
Kim Nam-ju, you study engineering.
Kwon Hyeon-guk. Class of 2000.
And you study German literature, right?
Not Nam-ju. "Soo." It's Kim Nam-soo.
- Kim Nam-soo.
- Right, soo.
Now, let me introduce our club executives.
Let's start with our treasurer.
MAGIC HOUR NEWBIE WELCOME PARTY
Hi, everyone.
I'm Park Kyu-ho, the treasurer.
Do you see that guy over there?
The one wearing the hoodie.
Finance sounds like a drag, huh?
He also studies management.
He's in the same department as me.
I've had my eye on him
since freshman orientation.
Everyone says he's secretly
a photography major though.
Next!
- They're dating.
- What?
The treasurer
and head of planning are dating.
How do you know?
He wiped dust off her hair
and even brushed it.
It was totally smooth.
It's a hidden talent of mine. Listen.
It might look like
everyone's paying attention,
but really, there's constant
back and forth. Of what?
Of vibes.
Hello. I'm Kim Sang-hak
from the research team.
You can think of our research team
as the embodiment of photography
in every aspect.
From the technical aspects
of taking photos
to development, printing, and history.
Anyone with a genuine interest
in photography is welcome.
That's me! I'll join the research team!
- Who is that?
- We'd love to have you.
And if any of you
are carrying around an old film roll
in the hopes of getting it developed,
you should join us immediately.
Come on, just go ahead and say
you want Tri-X to join you.
Thanks for listening!
What's Tri-X?
You don't even know Tri-X?
Tell me. What is it?
- It's just--
- Oh my! Hey.
Wow, you seem to be quite the drinker.
I look forward to our time together.
Thank you!
Hello. My name's Ryu Eun-jung--
Tri-X!
I'm a humanities major,
hoping to study Korean literature.
- And you use Tri-X.
- Yes, she does!
Nice to meet you!
Welcome!
Fold a finger
if your current GPA falls below 3.7.
Why aren't you targeting the newbies?
Make them fold first.
Those who are dating, fold.
- How's that targeting the newbies?
- Exactly!
Fold if you've kissed
within the past 24 hours.
Seriously?
Fold if you're handsome!
That doesn't include you guys.
Here I go. I'm folding!
Now drink up!
Keep going.
Humanities, fold.
We finally got Eun-jung.
- Bottoms up!
- I'll drink for her.
- Man, that's embarrassing!
- She doesn't like you!
It's Eun-jung's turn now. Everyone hush.
Non-freshmen, fold.
Nice one, Ryu Eun-jung!
- Bottoms up!
- Will you be okay?
- Eun-jung's drinking!
- Drink up!
Mom.
How did I get home last night?
You need to ask how you got home?
Way to go, Eun-jung.
Nice going!
It won't happen again.
What time did I get in?
I don't know! Maybe 2:00 a.m.
The seniors from your club
brought you home.
Seniors? Who?
There was a girl called Cho something,
and the other one was
Sang-hyeok? Right, Sang-hyeok.
And what did you say to them?
What do you think I said?
I gave them a piece of my mind
for getting you so drunk!
There's rice porridge in the pot.
If that ever happens again, I swear…
- Hello?
- Excuse me!
Hello?
How's the hangover?
Fine. I heard that you brought me home.
Did you totally black out?
I think so…
Don't you remember, "Excuse me"?
"Excuse me"?
You kept saying, "Excuse me!"
and scolding Sang-hak.
I did?
Sang-hak's probably feeling super dejected
right about now.
I can't remember a thing. Could you…
Excuse me!
Never ever!
…look like a fool?
That guy? I'd never date him!
Never ever!
Oh my God.
What have I done?
Everyone I meet keeps saying, "Excuse me!"
You would have done the same.
When you first said, "Excuse me,"
everyone went silent.
Then we all burst out laughing.
You're such a hoot when you're drunk!
I remember saying, "Excuse me,"
but I don't remember why.
Why I said that to Sang-hak
in the first place.
Said what?
That I wouldn't date him.
That's because I was on a roll.
On a roll?
The treasurer and head of planning.
Hyeon-jin and beanie guy!
- Damn, how did you know?
- She's spot on.
Polka dot and that guy!
Yeah, we're dating!
Everyone was in awe that night
because I sniffed out every couple.
And lastly,
let me make a prediction.
Kim Sang-hak
and Eun-jung!
They'll be dating within a month!
Come on. Sang-hak just wanted her
to join the research team.
Want to bet 10,000 won?
Whether Eun-jung and Sang-hak
will be dating within a month?
Be honest with me, bro.
Do you think you'll date Tri-X or not?
Excuse me!
And excuse you!
Why are you all making me
look like a fool?
I'm telling you now.
That guy?
I'd never ever date that guy!
I'm never dating him!
Why would I say that?
Oh, poor you.
SEOUL CAMERA SUPPLY
CAMERAS AND FILM PHOTOGRAPHY
Hello.
Looking for something?
I wanted to buy some film…
Could I please get three,
no, four rolls of Tri-X
and a 52 mm UV filter?
Need a bag?
No. I can carry it all in this.
It's 2,200 won for each roll
and 12,300 won for the UV filter,
so your total is 21,100 won.
I see we have a customer.
One second.
Here. 8,900 won change.
Thank you.
Bye.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
- Do you know her?
- She's just a freshman.
"Just a freshman."
That meant
that I no longer meant anything to him.
That I was a nobody.
Despite my efforts to stop…
my eyes kept drifting to him.
Everything about him…
seemed to hold so much meaning.
- Eun-jung, I must ask.
- Yes?
Are you dating Sang-hak?
No.
Nice! Kim A-ra, give me 10,000 won.
It's been a month, and they're not dating.
Pay up.
- Give me the money.
- Seriously?
Jeez, read the room.
Yes, Su-mi.
I don't think I'll be able to make it.
Something's come up at home.
I'll join you next time.
I won't miss the next one. All right, bye.
Why use family matters as an excuse?
You even bought sneakers for the trip.
We have 40 kilograms' worth
of injeolmi orders.
Having Eun-jung help out
makes things easier.
Eun-jung's faster
at making these than you.
- Is my order ready?
- Yes, hey.
- Hello.
Eun-jung, you're here too.
You're even prettier
now that you're in university.
Eun-jung, do you like being in university?
It's better than being in high school.
No more late night classes.
You're so lucky.
It must be so nice to be 20!
It's such a wonderful age.
You're like a flower blooming.
I could have cried.
Because this isn't how I'd imagined
being 20 would be.
I imagined it to be
more exhilarating.
Super exciting.
Just as she had said…
blooming like a flower.
Sang-hak's not coming to Pohang either
because of you.
Why?
How would I know?
Why can't you guys just get over it?
If you're not dating, you're not.
Why miss the photography trip?
- Hello.
- Here to work on your photos?
Go on. No one's inside.
Sang-hak seonbae.
Are you really not going
on the photography trip because of me?
Because I'll find it uncomfortable?
If we'd both feel awkward…
it's only right that I don't go.
How would that be right?
I've already been there twice.
And I'm older than you.
But still…
If I'd known…
that I made you so uncomfortable,
I wouldn't have acted that way.
I've been meaning to tell you this.
I'm sorry for overstepping.
That won't happen again,
so just enjoy being in the club.
It would be a shame
to give up something you enjoy
over someone you dislike.
I don't dislike you.
You didn't do anything
for me to dislike you.
It's my fault, really.
I'm the one who feels uncomfortable.
All right, then. Let's hear it.
Why do I make you so uncomfortable?
It's just…
You said you disliked me
from the very start.
I said that?
Yes.
So tell me,
why do you hate Sang-hak so much?
Because he's Sang-hak.
Yeah, he's Sang-hak.
It may not seem like it, but he is
the most popular guy in our club.
Do you really not like him?
From the very first moment I saw him,
he's been Sang-hak.
Makes me so uncomfortable…
That…
was about your name.
That was about how you have the same name
as someone I used to know.
The same name?
Hold up.
How much of a jerk was he for you to…
What kind of person is he?
That Kim Sang-hak.
Just Sang-hak.
Not Kim Sang-hak.
Just Sang-hak oppa.
I had a crush on him,
and seeing you reminds me of him.
1/60th of a second.
It's him, isn't it? The one you mentioned
on your registration form.
Collecting time.
Did you bring up the dragonfly net
because you read that?
Of course.
I didn't know that and thought…
I was shocked you had the same name,
but you kept saying the same things.
He's actually the reason
I joined the club, but--
So I don't share a name with someone
who was a jerk to you, right?
I share it
with someone you like?
Then why do I make you so uncomfortable?
Because you're so nice to me.
You were nice to me for no reason.
- Seriously?
- And asked me to join the research team.
It's strange because I haven't done
anything to deserve it.
Why wouldn't you deserve it?
On the first day we met,
you made me laugh and run around campus.
And it's not like I was the only one
who wanted you on my team.
Jeong-seon wanted you to join planning,
and the others, they…
Man, I'm really telling you everything.
I played so much rock, paper, scissors
to bring you to the research team…
Anyways…
Come tomorrow. That place is great.
Is that a promise?
Okay.
If you come early,
I'll buy you a popsicle.
A popsicle?
Yes. A popsicle.
SANGBONG TERMINAL
A popsicle, huh?
A popsicle?
Eun-jung.
Hello.
You're here so early.
You do know it's the 6:50 bus, right?
Yes.
That reminds me.
- I'll pay you the club fee.
- Sure.
Chips, anyone?
Hi, guys!
- Hello.
- Stay seated, guys.
I need to pee. Don't you need to go?
Yeah, I'll go.
Everyone, the bus is here.
Please board by 6:45.
Okay.
You take the window seat.
I always pass out on buses.
- Sure. Why don't you get on first?
- Okay.
KIM SANG-HAK SEONBAE
Lee Ki-yeong, please come
to the lost and found center
on the second floor…
Stop it.
- I'm feeling sick.
- Can you get on the bus?
No.
Sang-hak said he'd come too.
He did, didn't he?
- Sang-hak's coming?
- Yes.
- I thought he couldn't?
- He said he would.
Get on the bus. I'll try calling him.
Let's go.
Hold on.
Didn't our head of research say
he'd come too?
He's not picking up,
so I guess he's sleeping in.
Don't worry about him.
He'll find his way there.
He's never been late for anything.
Hey. Is everything okay?
Everything was most definitely not okay.
Otherwise, he would be here.
For no reason,
my mind turned to Cheon Sang-hak…
and that smile of his.
That had been the last of him.
MUNGYEONG REST STOP
Sang-hak seonbae is just sleeping in.
He's not Sang-hak oppa.
He's asleep. That's all.
The view's gorgeous!
Dang, you scared me. Where were you?
Hey, Kim Sang-hak!
We thought you were still asleep at home.
How did you get here before us?
I flew here, okay?
And how exactly did you fly here?
How do you think? By plane, of course.
You rode a plane here?
Don't eat all the popsicles
in the freezer!
- Popsicles? There are popsicles!
- Where are they?
Guys, get inside. There are popsicles!
- Come inside.
- Where are they?
Ryu Eun-jung!
Eun-jung, take me with you!
Eun-jung.
Are you crying?
No.
Hey, come on. Were you worried?
That's why I took a plane here.
Do you know how much it cost me?
Honestly, I flew here
because I didn't want you to worry.
You'll laugh if I tell you.
I swear I left early this morning,
but my phone fell between the platforms
when I was transferring--
I thought you'd died.
Died?
Hey, come on, now…
I don't know why I cried so hard.
I thought it strange
even as the tears fell.
I had never cried so hard,
not even when Sang-hak died.
Sang-hak seonbae later told me
that seeing me cry explained a lot.
Including why I acted so strange
after hearing his name…
who owned the film roll I brought,
and what had happened to them.
Will you be my girlfriend?
I like you.
I like you too.
Guys!
What are you doing over there?
Hyeon-guk.
Give A-ra 10,000 won.
- What?
- Why?
We're dating!
Let's go eat popsicles.
Oh my God, they're actually dating!
Ryu Eun-jung!
I didn't even know you had taken these.
- Not one photo, but three.
- It's actually five.
- Five?
- Yeah.
SPRING OF 2002
Here. Look.
You made this contact print?
It's so pretty.
Are you calling yourself pretty?
Yeah.
So you liked me since then.
Why didn't you say so?
Back then, I just couldn't read your mind.
You had this mysterious charm.
Now you're…
An open book, aren't I?
I tell all before you get curious.
You know yourself well.
It seems like you've done
so many exhibitions.
I did start photography in middle school.
I'll go.
Welcome.
Thank you, ma'am. Have a good day!
What's that?
What exhibition was this?
It was with a club I was in
during my gap year.
Why?
Oh, it's nothing.
I thought it might be someone I know,
but I don't think it is.
Yeah, it's definitely not.
My uncle's here.
- I see Sang-hak's here.
- Hello, sir.
- You good?
- Yes.
How was the turnout?
A handful of freshmen took our leaflets,
but I only saw one person
fill out a registration form.
I see why freshmen are so rare.
That reminds me
of something funny from earlier.
- The one who filled out a form.
- Yeah?
They just showed up to our booth and asked
if broke people can take up photography.
MAGIC HOUR
29TH RECRUITMENT
Can I
learn photography even if I'm broke?
You can.
But you'd need a camera,
even if it's not an expensive one.
Do you have one?
That person then took a camera
out of a bag and showed it to me.
Guess what it was.
A Leica M3.
A Leica?
M3… Isn't that the model you want?
Yeah. It's the camera of my dreams.
Broke but has a Leica?
That's hilarious.
Right? The reason for joining
is even funnier.
We all cracked up after reading the form.
What is this?
"Can't say…"
- Huh?
- What the…
- What is…
- Is this really…
What is this?
REASON FOR JOINING:
CAN'T SAY
That's what was written? "Can't say"?
Yeah. Funny, isn't it?
How funny.
When is your mother being discharged?
The day after tomorrow.
That's good. So you can make it
to the newbie welcome party, right?
I guess so.
Hello. I broke up with my girlfriend
three months ago.
- Oh dear!
- Poor you.
I'm Kim Dae-kyu, a social science student.
Class of 2002.
I dream of walking this university campus
with a newfound love!
Blue jumper across from you.
Hello. I'm Cheon Sang-yeon.
Class of 2002. School of Engineering.
I should technically be a grade higher.
I didn't intend to take a gap year…
It was Sang-yeon.
I didn't really go to school.
I much preferred going out.
The "yeon" in my name means swallow,
so I'm quite the carefree bird.
I've never taken photos before,
but I figured it could be fun.
Do you have an older sister?
No, I don't have an older sister,
but I do have
a good-for-nothing older brother.
Thanks for the warm welcome!
Subtitle translation by: Jimin Choi